Is that Captain Levi?
I don't know what happened,
but we're lucky it did.
The biggest threat we faced
is lying in a bloody heap.
We should put one
in his head, just in case.
There's no need.
He was caught in a Thunder Spear
explosion at point-blank range.
It shredded his guts.
Killed him instantly,
from what I can tell.
Then give him to me.
I wanna check his pulse
for myself, so hand him over.
[JAEGERIST 76B]
Floch!
What's happening to it?
Did it just die?
That's not it.
Their bodies don't suck in steam
like that when they disappear.
[splash]
[Gasps] They're escaping!
[JAEGERIST 76B]
Shit!
[JAEGERIST 76C]
After them!
[JAEGERIST 76B]
They can't get away!
Zeke. How did you
end up inside that Titan?
[ZEKE]
Couldn't tell you.
I saw a girl I didn't know
sculpting the earth
to reform my body.
[ZEKE] In that empty place,
all I could do was watch.
[ZEKE] It felt like I had
been there for years.
But also, like it was
over in an instant.
I remember.
Staring at the sky.
Were those the Paths I saw?
Have to ask,
the Survey Corps had
30 scouts guarding
your location.
I'm assuming you turned
them all into Titans,
but where are they now?
Gone. That's the long
and short of it.
This means our biggest
obstacles are dealt with.
No one's left to get in our way.
Let's go.
[ZEKE] All we can do now
is keep moving forward.
Right, Eren?
♪ Opening Song ♪
[Roars]
What the hell?
I think it's beginning.
The Titans have started to move.
Is that you, Galliard?
Didn't quite get him,
but it was worth a shot.
Wait, Pieck! You're not
actually a traitor?
Gabi! You really thought
I'd sell out my comrades?
Well, you said if we
kept fighting for Marley,
then we'd end up
getting put down!
Look up there.
[PIECK]
I don't trust Marley one bit.
Having said that,
I trust the comrades
who've fought at
my side completely.
[MAGATH]
There's the smoke signal.
Pieck and Galliard
tracked him down
and forced him out
into the open.
The Founder is here.
Let's pay him back for Liberio.
I want that bastard dead!
[MARLEYAN SOLDIER 76A]
Go, go, go!
Hey. What now?
Hey, Pieck? Wake up, Pieck!
Porco!
[BOTH scream]
[PIECK]
That hurt!
[yells]
[EREN] I can't believe Marley
was desperate enough
to try something like this.
They're practically
coming in blind.
Why would they put what's left
of their military at risk?
[YELENA]
Eren! Can you hear me?
Abandon your
Titan body immediately!
We need to get you inside.
Then you can escape underground
with the War Hammer's power!
You'll be at a disadvantage
if you fight here!
[YELENA]
Eren!
[EREN]
Let's do this. Reiner.
Of course, you're here.
Who else could talk Marley into
doing something so stupid?
[YELENA]
Mobilize all units!
Hurry! Protect Eren!
Eren. Why?
[Roars]
[GABI gasps]
[GABI]
Reiner! He really came for us!
Pieck! I'm over here!
Gabi!
[GABI]
Commander Magath?
Dammit all, Braun!
Did I order you to
pursue the enemy?
[GABI gasps]
I'm sorry, sir!
What the hell's
the matter with you?
[COLT]
Gabi!
[GABI]
Colt!
Why isn't Falco here?
Is he safe?
[GABI]
He's alive.
He should be in
that big building.
He got some of Zeke's
spinal fluid in his mouth,
so they're keeping
him locked up.
[Gasps] You're
kidding me, right?
[PIECK TITAN] He's being
detained along with roughly
300 local soldiers who also
drank the spinal fluid.
I counted about 500 free
enemy troops in the area,
but I didn't see
any sign of Zeke.
We couldn't wait around
after what Reiner told us.
Is it possible that they could
activate the Founder's power?
[PIECK TITAN] I'm not sure.
But I know this much.
That power is the strongest
weapon they've got―
the ace up their sleeve.
There must be some reason
they haven't played it yet.
So I'm guessing that there's
still something keeping Eren
from using the
Founder's ability.
And what's that?
Some condition he hasn't met?
[GABI gasps]
[GABI] Wait. "You now possess
the Founding Titan
as well as a Titan
with royal blood."
[GABI] I heard Zeke say those
exact words to the enemy
on the airship
that attacked Marley!
But what does that mean?
Royal blood?
Wait, he couldn't have been
talking about himself, could he?
His parents were part of
the Restorationist leadership.
It's possible.
[PIECK TITAN] He's always had
powers above and beyond
what the Beast usually would.
This might be the explanation.
If it is, then Zeke's
absence could be
what's keeping Eren from
using the Founder's power.
We have to prevent the two
of them from making contact.
Commander Magath. Reiner is―
[MAGATH]
It's "General" now,
and Marley's shield
won't break that easily.
No, it isn't just
Marley anymore.
He's shielding the entire world.
We're humanity's final hope.
Killing the Founder
won't solve this.
It'll just kick the can
down the road.
So instead, we'll have
a Warrior eat him,
and bring an end to
two thousand years of hatred.
Now I'll make you pay.
[GALLIARD] For the way
you trampled my home!
[REINER] Eren. You're no threat
to us on your own.
This is the end for you.
So give up already!
[JAEGERIST 76F]
Go! Finish them!
[JAEGERIST 76G]
We brought their favorite snack.
Let's hit 'em with
the Thunder Spears!
[SCOUTS gasp]
No.
The hell was that?
Load another round, soldier!
Yes, sir!
Blew his brains clean out.
We crippled the Attack Titan's
motor control, sir!
Nice shot, Commander Magath.
[MAGATH]
You mean, "General."
Much as I hate to say it,
that's just how far
the Marleyan army's fallen.
Her top artilleryman is the only
one left to steer the ship.
Dammit, the Armor and Jaw
are gonna get away!
[JAEGERIST 76I]
Contact!
[JAEGERIST 76J]
Up on the roofs!
[JAEGERIST 76D]
We're outnumbered!
[JAEGERIST 76E] It's fine,
we're faster. Flank 'em!
[VOLUNTEER 76A]
No way.
I thought the Marleyan officer
corps was nearly wiped out.
How did they coordinate this
attack in less than a month?
If this goes on...
They're gonna capture
the Founder!
[YELENA]
Eren. You're not like the rest.
You never were.
[YELENA]
You're special.
[Roars]
[MAGATH]
Let him wear himself out.
The War Hammer's powerful,
but its ability burns
a great deal of energy.
[MAGATH] Don't forget.
Willy Tybur sacrificed himself
to offer us a chance
to launch this assault.
Remember the message
he died to deliver.
At this point, the only hope for
humanity is another Helos.
A hero to save our world.
[REINER]
Come on, Eren. Give up.
[Roars]
You've lost this fight.
[Screaming]
[REINER] It's over,
we've suffered enough.
We all have,
and that includes you.
[ONYANKOPON panting]
[JEAN]
Onyankopon?
Hey! What the hell's going on?
[ONYANKOPON] Marley launched
an attack on the island
with their airship fleet.
They've got 500 soldiers,
plus the Armored,
Jaw, and Cart Titans.
Eren's still out there
fighting them on his own.
But he's struggling.
He's not gonna last long.
[ONYANKOPON] Marley is gonna
take the Founder!
You have to help!
Join us. Protect Eren!
[CONNY]
Are you shitting me?
We're not on the same side!
This is your battle!
You already betrayed us once.
Why the hell would we
do as you say?
I'm sorry! I never wanted this,
but Yelena would've
put a bullet in my head
if I hadn't gone along
with her plan!
Huh? You think I wanna
hear your excuses?
You've been acting
like our friend
while you used that wine
to take over Paradis!
I'm sick of it.
I'm so sick of getting betrayed!
Reiner. Bertholdt. Annie.
You.
Even Eren's betrayed us!
I can't stand it!
Why should we do
a damn thing for him, huh?
Why should we
save him just so he can
stop any of us from
ever having kids? Well?
[ONYANKOPON]
Wait.
I'd like to hear
him out, at least. 'Kay?
[ONYANKOPON coughing]
I had no idea that Yelena
was plotting any of this.
The tainted wine or
the euthanization plan.
None of the Volunteers
were told anything.
Huh?!
[NICOLO]
He's telling the truth.
We never discussed the tainted
wine with the Volunteers.
Yelena ordered us
not to mention it to them.
[ONYANKOPON]
What's more.
I don't want to see
the Eldian people euthanized!
Our goal was to build a new
Paradis alongside all of you.
To rise up and
beat Marley together!
That's why we left everything
behind to come here!
I gave up my whole life for
the people of this island.
Because...
I thought together,
we could create
a better future on Paradis.
But there is no future
without children!
If this euthanization
plan succeeds,
then everything
we've sacrificed―
It'll all be for nothing!
You have to believe me.
He's telling the truth.
Armin?
Years ago, when you
first came here,
you said something
that stuck with me.
That we Subjects of Ymir
exist because we're wanted.
That the world
is more interesting
with different kinds of people.
I think you believe that.
And I think that belief goes
against everything Zeke's doing.
You meant all the things
you said, right?
Then get back on
your feet. Onyankopon.
Thank you.
Well, for what it's worth,
I believe you, too.
But now what?
If we help Eren and Zeke
fight off the Marleyan army,
they'll just end up
going through with
the euthanization plan, right?
Well. We'll at least have
a chance to stop them.
Because if those two die,
the whole world is gonna
come crashing down on us.
[CONNY] So what are you trying
to say we should do, then?
If nothing else, we can
activate the rumbling
and show the world that we're
capable of punching back!
[CONNY] Huh? You wanna give 'em
a taste of the rumbling?
Hey, Mikasa, what do you think?
Do you want to go help Eren?
I would say yes. Except, knowing what he told me,
I'm not sure if I want to or if
my blood is telling me to.
[MIKASA]
I'm an Ackerman.
My will's not my own.
Huh?
Look, Mikasa.
I think Eren made that up
to mess with your head.
No, he was on to something.
He asked if I get
headaches, and I do.
What makes you
think he was lying?
What makes me think h―
Guys.
Do you actually
believe Eren wants to
stop all Eldians
from having children?
You honestly think
he'd go along with that?
It doesn't really strike me
as something Eren would want,
but I can't say that it's
more than he's willing―
Well I can say it!
He would never do that!
You don't think so?
Did you think he'd work
with Zeke and Yelena?
He's just pretending to!
Don't you see?
Eren's the one with
the Founding Titan's power,
so he doesn't
need to fight Zeke!
Things were different
when Yelena
first came to him with the plan.
There's no telling
what she might have done
if he had refused to join her.
He didn't have
any options back then!
But now, Eren has Yelena
completely convinced
that he's on her side,
and the Volunteers have
gotten him in contact with Zeke.
He's in control.
He can use the rumbling
to protect the island!
Nobody will dare lay a hand on
Paradis for the next 50 years!
[Screaming]
[EREN TITAN screaming]
♪ Ending Song ♪
[NARRATOR] The earth trembles
as the Titans clash.
While their fight rages above,
the people at their feet
must take up arms
and charge into the fray,
like it or not.
Next episode: "Sneak Attack."